"Company Worker - Ukai Tsuneo (47)"
He spoke it!
"Role of Sakamoto Ryoma, Sakuraba Reiichi"
"Conan Special Drama Kudo Shinichi's
Kyoto Shinsengumi Murder Case"
You rebel ronin who defy the Shogunate!
"Osaka's High School Detective - Hattori Heiji"
This Shinsengumi, Okita Soji,
will be your opponent.
En garde.
This isn’t over!
-Cut! Cut!
-You there!
How many times do I have to tell you?
When you're stabbed, just die
already! Just drop dead!
This Mori Kogoro will not fall so easily!
"Private Detective - Mori Kogoro"
Fool! You're just a mere extra!
Alright! One more time!
"Heiji's Childhood Friend Toyama Kazuha"
-One more time, please!
-No, no! This is my spotlight.
Look, it's also written right here.
You are the protagonist!,
Ryoma's Holiday.
That's a common dream to write down.
Fool! You samurai boy!
What is life without a dream?!
It's still too early to give up.
I'll appeal directly to the Director!
Director! Please give me a
chance! I'll do my best...
Ran, it's been ages!
Actually, when Heiji was in
the middle of a kendo contest...
...he had been scouted
for a historical film.
So we're now in Kyoto
shooting it, but...
"Why don't you come see
the shoot?"
Sounds fun!
Shinichi, do you want
to go together?
We can zoom over there by plane.
That’s dangerous!
I'm not interested in movies.
Actually you're just jealous about
Hattori's achievements, right?
Fool! No way!
Kudo-sempai! Kyaa!
-How was your last case?
-That was just an easy trick.
-Please give me your autograph!
-Please shake my hand!
-Another time.
-Kyaa! So cool!
Ehh... Even if you're not
interested in movies...
...you are interested in the junior girls.
What are you saying?
You turn down an invitation
from your childhood friend...
But you'll be giving those
junior girls your autograph?
Ah, alright already. I understand.
-Excuse me!
- I'll go.
It's fine if I go, right?
"High School Student Detective -
Kudo Shinichi"
My name is Kudo Shinichi.
I'm a famous high school
student detective.
But one day when I went with my
childhood friend Ran to an amusement park,
I witnessed a scene of some men in
black involved in some suspicious deal.
And then one of those men made me
take a poison known as Apoptoxin 4869.
When I woke up,
my body had shrunken.
If they knew that
Kudo Shinichi was still alive...
...the Black Organization could bring
harm to people around me.
Naming myself Edogawa Conan...
I solved cases while looking for
information on those men.
But this story was from long
before I became Edogawa Conan.
"Conan Special Drama Kudo Shinichi's
Kyoto Shinsengumi Murder Case"
"LUNA Airlines/Flight 576"
What is it?
I just heard a scream.
There...
This is...
He's dead.
That Shinichi...
Where did he go?
-I'm Sato of the MPD.
-I'm Takagi of the same.
No one has touched
the body, right?
Well, strange young man earlier.
-A strange young man?
-Yes.
-Excuse us.
-I'm sorry.
The cause of death was probably...
...suffocation due to a
cervical spinal cord injury.
The weapon was the sharpened
point of a dull-edged tool.
Something like an ice pick.
When a human is struck here,
in the respiratory center of the medulla...
The respiratory neurons
pathways become impaired...
...causing the victim to be unable to
breathe nor speak leading to death.
But before the victim was struck,
he was made to inhale chemicals...
...causing him to fall into a coma first.
But don't worry.
The criminal is still here in
this huge clump of iron.
Hey! Who are you?!
Yes. That was the first page.
Kudo Shinichi.
Detective.
This was the first case of high school
student detective, Kudo Shinichi.
"The Closed-room Murder
at 10,000 meters"
The victim is Otaka Kazuhiro, 29.
A professional photographer.
About half a year ago...
...I read a newspaper article about
him winning the Press Photo Award.
By the way, his passport was
inside his inner vest pocket.
It was important to him, and
that may be why he put it in there.
- Sorry, but this is police work!
- Hey, get out!
Children should stay out of this!
Ah, since we would like to take
some photos of the crime scene...
...could we borrow
a camera from you?
I took a photo of it already.
Shinichi?
Based upon the condition of postmortem
lividity and the rigidity of his jaw...
...I believe that 1 to 2 hours
have passed since his death.
I don’t know where
you heard all these, but...
There are 3 things bothering me.
First is that while there are bloodstains on
the wall where the corpse was resting…
But there aren't any clinging
to his clothes at all.
Second is that there is another wound
to the lower left of the mortal wound.
A mark as if he had been scratched
with the edge of something.
Thirdly is that the insides of his pants
pockets are soaked for some reason.
Even if he had poked his wet hands into
them, they wouldn't have gotten that wet.
-Ouch!
-Stop this!
-There's no reason to hit me.
-I told you this is police work!
Um, in order to check for witnesses
of any suspicious people...
-Could you please gather the passengers?
-There's no need for that.
There are just 4 suspects.
Wait!
Why are you saying such bossy things
for! You're just a high school student!
Why would you say that
there are only 4 of them?
My seat was at the far back.
People going to the restrooms
would have had to go pass me...
...and there were
no passengers behind me.
Of those who did go to the restroom
around the estimated time of death...
...aside from the victim,
there were just 4 people.
By checking their faces,
I would recognize them instantly.
Don't tell me you were
awake all night?
Well, I guess.
I just couldn't sleep that easily.
Fool!
Seeing that sleeping face of yours...
There was no way
I could just calmly go to sleep.
-You said something?
-Ah, nothing.
Well, since you're willing
to go that far...
Let's see if you know
who those 4 people are.
Sure.
Let's see...
The 4 people are...
Ah...
This woman here and
the woman next to her...
The man across from
them in the aisle seat...
And this foreigner in
the seat in front of them.
Otaka's seat was...right here, correct?
They were all sitting in proximity
to the victim, weren't they?
"Victim"?
What do you mean by that?
Excuse me.
For now, the four of you
please come to rear restrooms.
We'll discuss the circumstances there.
No... Otaka! Otaka!!
Cannot be...
-No way...
-Excuse me, you are?
Ah... Along with these two women,
we're photographers just like Otaka.
Say, do I have the right
to hear what happened?
Well, since you are
the victim’s associates.
You were sitting near the victim, Otaka,
but what is your connection to him?
I had no relation to him.
I'm just an ordinary salaryman
off on a business trip.
I and Saginuma were traveling
along with Otaka as friends.
Tsugumi was... Otaka's girlfriend.
And the one other person is a foreigner.
-Takagi, how's your English?
-Ah, I can speak a little.
-Hmmm, let's see...
-(What was your relationship to the victim?)
(It was my first time to see him.
I just came to Japan to buy artwork.)
(Thanks!)
He said that he wasn't
an acquaintance of Otaka's...
...and only came to Japan
to buy artwork.
Thank you!
Ah! Could it be...
Once we get there, these negatives
will fetch a high price...
...and we can vacation all we want!
You should be happy having
such a nice boyfriend, right!
-Wait Otaka, be quiet.
-Eh?
Could you be quiet?
-Everyone is trying to sleep.
-Ah, my bad.
I'll be careful next time!
Otaka! Stop it already!
Yes, yes. I understand.
Such a scary woman.
Right, Saginuma?
What a boring guy, the bastard.
Guess I'll take a nap, too.
Maybe he was killed
because of those negatives...
But no negatives were found
on Otaka's corpse.
Eh? He should have been keeping
them in his inner vest pocket.
I see. I'm sure the criminal
took them away.
Firstly, would each of the 4 of you...
...tell me what happened
when you went to the restroom?
When I returned from the restroom...
Otaka was in his seat.
I remembered feeling a little ill,
so I called the stewardess.
-Can I help you?
-I'm sorry.
Do you have any medicine
to stop motion sickness?
Yes. Please wait just a moment.
I also saw the male victim from
the opposite aisle over there.
Why were you in the opposite aisle?
I was just wandering around
since I was restless.
Though I had been
sleeping soundly...
...because of a noisy passenger,
I was woken up.
It’s that man. It was when
Tsugumi was asking for medicine...
...that I saw the male victim.
I went to the restroom
right after that.
I was woken up when the
stewardess brought the medicine...
But at that time
Otaka wasn't there any longer.
Did you take the motion
sickness medicine I gave you?
Yeah...
That's strange...
I’ve given some to Saginuma, too,
but it seems to work on him.
In that case,
why don't we switch seats?
If you're next to a window,
maybe that'll change your mood.
Yes, alright.
Thanks.
Excuse me.
The medicine is for her.
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
-Here.
Oh. Where's Otaka?
Ah...Looks like he went somewhere.
To the restroom? Otaka...
I then went to the restroom.
Then it can be said Otaka left
his seat to go to the restroom...
...after Tsugumi asked for the medicine
but before it was brought to her, right?
Then after that, Chizuru you said
you went to the restroom...
I didn't kill him!
That said, when I went to
the restroom, Otaka was still alive!
When I asked if he was okay and
knocked, he knocked back!
You knew exactly which restroom
he entered, didn't you?
Eh?
Because the locks to all
the other restrooms were open.
Then, the last person...
(When were you in the bathroom?)
(I don't remember what time it was.)
He says he doesn't remember
when he went in.
What's the matter?
Well...the smell of
his cologne is so strong.
And now we've heard the stories of
everyone who went to the restroom, but...
Just a moment please.
There was one other person
who left their seat.
This man.
Huh?!
I was asleep the entire time!
Your seat was directly behind
the murdered Otaka, right?
When Otaka was sleeping,
there was no one in that seat.
In other words,
you must have left your seat!
Stop bullshittting me!
Didn’t he say that
the 4 of you left your seats?
-Right?
-Eh? Ah, well...
Hey! Be certain!
Thing is...
I have a feeling I was
distracted for a moment...
-Eh?!
-Well, it was you...
Anyhow, rather than listening
to our testimonies...
...wouldn’t it be faster to find either
the negatives or the murder weapon?
That's certainly true.
Well then, let’s do a body check on
all of you and a check of your luggage.
-Are you okay with that?
-Huh? Me, too?
Would that inconvenience
you somehow?
Let's see. Next is Tsugumi.
In here we have a passport, a wallet...
...and a sewing set with scissors...
...but it would be impossible
to kill someone with these.
Have you checked
the contents of the pen?
Yes?
It would be possible to hide the deadly
weapon as part of its core section.
Core?
Core… the core!
I'll check the core now.
Ah look, the core is in good order.
Let's see, next is...
...oh, it’s Mr. Edward.
This is a checkbook from
the American National Bank...
Ah, you...
(What were you going
to use this checkbook for?)
(I brought it to buy pieces
at a Japanese auction.)
(Ah, collecting artwork
is a hobby of mine.)
(Unfortunately, it was all junk
and a waste of time.)
He says it was in order to purchase
artwork but that he didn't get to use it.
(I can tell you have a great sense
of art from that beautiful watch.)
-(Can I take a look?)
-(Sure.)
Though the smell of his cologne
was quite strong around his neck...
...I couldn't smell anything
from his wrist.
Didn't he put any on his wrist?
(Thanks.)
Then, next is...
Saginuma, right?
Here you are.
Knock yourself out.
Ah, um, this, too...
Let's see...
You seem to have a lot of medicine
to prevent motion sickness.
I'm weak when it comes
to vehicles, you see.
I’ve gotten them from
Tsugumi and Chizuro, right?
Yeah.
These are...negatives, aren't they?
What about them?
I'm a photographer,
so of course I'd have negatives!
The person with the woman
in these pictures...
It's the American Senator,
Dickson, isn't it?
That's fine, isn't it?
Aren't those the same
negatives as Otaka's?
By "the same," do you mean the ones
that were missing from the victim's corpse?
-So if you have those…
-Saginuma...
Did you kill Otaka and
then steal these negatives?
These are mine!
I took these together with Otaka!
They turned out worse
than Otaka’s but…
I was planning to sell them
to a newspaper, too.
You guys heard Otaka
talking about that, right?
Well, it wasn't me!
Well, if you are suspect me,
then bring out the murder weapon!
The criminal should still have
the murder weapon, right?!
But the murder weapon
hasn't been found anywhere yet.
There’s still a place where
we can find the murder weapon.
We did the body checks
just now, right?!
No.
The most important place
has been overlooked.
The most important place?!
The murdered Otaka's luggage.
That's all that's left.
Here.
Ah, which is Otaka's luggage?
-Is something the matter?
-Ah, no...
I just remember when he had left his bag
behind at his studio one week ago...
It had been cut to shreds
with sharp object...
So I bought him
a new bag for travel.
I think it's possible that the
negatives were in his previous bag...
...and someone may have
searching for them, right?
Yes.
There doesn't seem
to be anything here...
...that could be used as
the murder weapon.
This is after all, just the deduction of
a high-school student playing detective.
What is with this case...
If the murder weapon
can't be found...
...I also won't be able to
figure out when Otaka was killed.
Is someone giving
a false testimony...?
Like I thought, you're
the criminal, aren't you?
Huh?
What are you saying?
When this lady was asking
the stewardess for the medicine...
...you weren't in the seat
behind the sleeping Otaka.
Just a minute! I was awake when
the stewardess brought the medicine...
...but Saginuma was sleeping
in the seat behind, right?
-Otaka was gone, though...
-There, see! Stop bullshitting!
But, even this stewardess
saw that, right?
Yes. I don't think he was there...
Hey, what are you two suggesting?!
Let's hear from the stewardess
who brought the medicine as well.
At the time Tsugumi asked
for the medicine...
...was this person in the
seat behind Otaka?
I was fast asleep, right?
Right!
Whether he was there or
whether he wasn't there...
-Otaka was there, wasn't he?
-That I do remember.
He was asleep, with an eye
mask and blanket put on.
Was there anyone in front of Otaka?
As I recall, there wasn't...
I know!
Saginuma's seat was,
if I remember...Right here.
I knew it!
There's no mistake.
The criminal is that person!
What happened all of a sudden?
What do you mean?
I know who the criminal is.
Eh? No way!?
All that's left is the
mysterious murder weapon.
Are you okay?
I'm fine, but...
Ah! No, no! You're wrong!
Hey! Where were
you touching me!?
It wasn't on purpose!
Still, they are bigger than
I thought they were.
Since Ran is a high school student.
Shinichi, you pervert!
That’s not what I meant...
I wanted to ask you this since you
have became a high school student...
Huh?
Wait... What is it...
Hurry and tell me.
I'm embarrassed for even asking it.
Most of them are like this lately...
-I see. So that's it...
-Huh?! How did that convince you?
I've figured it out at last.
The criminal's trump card for
how they ended the victim's life...
The trick of the murder weapon!
Chizuru.
Is it true that there was a returning
knock from the restroom?
Why do I need to lie about that?
Because it seems that you went to the
restroom after Otaka who was murdered.
In other words, she didn't lie.
When Chizuru knocked...
...there was someone else in the
restroom with the victim's corpse...
...other than the criminal.
-Eh?!
-Please remember.
There were bloodstains scattered...
...on the wall of the restroom that
got there during the time of the crime.
And yet, on the back of the body
which was leaning against the wall...
...there was no blood.
That was because the blood from the time
of Otaka's murder had dried on the wall...
And that someone other than the
criminal then moved his body afterwards.
Why was the body moved?
That's because they were
looking for those negatives...
...that Otaka should have
had on him.
Isn't that right...Mr. Edward?
When you were looking
for the negatives...
...you also checked
the pockets of his pants.
That was when the cologne on
your wrist got stuck to his pockets.
So in a rush, you washed your
hands and wet a handkerchief.
You then used that to wipe away
the unique smell from the pocket.
The only evidence
of that is your wrist...
It doesn't have cologne on it.
Edward...
You can actually
speak Japanese, can you?
Hurry and speak it
for your own sake.
-It's as this boy says.
-Eh?! He spoke Japanese!
The scandal photos
taken of Senator Dickson.
I was asked to purchase the negatives.
When I heard that he had
gone to the restroom...
...I thought that would be
a chance to do a trade with him.
But he was dead.
He was bent over at the waist.
Though I thought
it was wrong of me...
I searched his body
for the negatives.
Then, when I knocked,
the one who answered...
Otaka, are you okay?
I was surprised at the time.
No matter how much I looked for
them, I couldn't find those negatives.
Edward and Chizuru,
who knocked from outside...
...can't be considered
as the criminals.
That leaves 2 remaining suspects,
Ukai and Tsugumi.
Eh?!
What bothered me was
Ukai's testimony.
At the time Tsugumi
was asking for the medicine...
He says Saginuma wasn't in
his seat behind the victim, Otaka.
Well... I wasn't lying!
Even the stewardess saw that!
And I said I was asleep!
Neither of you two are lying.
It was the differing testimony
between you two...
...has provided an important
clue to finding the criminal.
Then you know
who the criminal is?
Who is it?
The criminal who
murdered Otaka was...
Tsugumi...you.
Eh?
You've gotta be joking!
Evidence!
Where's your evidence?!
There is proper evidence.
Because Tsugumi should still have
the murder weapon on her.
Tsugumi took the physical
search too, didn't she?
The weapon used to murder Otaka
wouldn't be considered suspicious.
It would also pass through the
metal detector at a boarding gate...
...and is a thing
only made for women.
Only made for women?
No, no, there couldn't be such
a convenient thing, could there?
There is.
It's Tsugumi's...
Ah! I know!
Yes.
The wire from the underwear
of Tsugumi's right breast.
-Underwear wire?!
-No, no...
It'd be impossible to kill
someone with something like that!
The wire had been
sharpened ahead of time...
...and then stabbed into
the back of his head.
Multiplied using the weight
from her entire body...
...it would reach
the cervical spinal cord.
It's a crime that even
a woman could commit.
The reason why the wire
wasn’t disposed of is...
...because should it be known
to be the murder weapon.
The woman without a wire
in her underwear...
...would have been
exposed as the criminal.
If so...If Tsugumi takes another
body check, it would be fine, right?
It's no use, Saginuma...
If they searched me again
they'd find out right away...
You...
Tsugumi...
To start off, Tsugumi was in the seat
next to the sleeping Chizuru...
...when Otaka went to the restroom.
And then, just as he
opened the door...
He was hit with a handkerchief
soaked in chemicals...
...and soon lost consciousness.
Removing the wire from
her underwear...
...she pierced Otaka's
cervical spinal cord.
Asphyxiating him to death.
That scratch wound on
his body was caused by...
...the end that hadn't been
sharpened, wasn't it?
To make it look as though the crime
had been over the negatives...
You used the scissors from your
sewing kit to cut up the negatives...
...and then flushed
them down the toilet.
And, when Tsugumi had returned
from the restroom to her seat...
She disguised Saginuma as Otaka
using a knit hat and eye mask.
Ma’am, can I help you?
I'm sorry.
Do you have medicine
for motion sickness?
Yes. Please wait just a moment.
That's why Ukai could mistake the
disguised Saginuma for being Otaka.
By doing that, Tsugumi created
an illusion for the time...
...when Otaka had gone
to the restroom.
Are you okay?
It was a dark cabin and...
...all that was sticking out from
the blanket was his nose and up.
It's reasonable for such
a misunderstanding.
Ah, the medicine is for her.
The evidence that Tsugumi used the
trick of disguising Saginuma was...
...this piece of negative that had
fallen into the seat next to him.
If a piece had gotten stuck to her clothes
while she was cutting up the negatives...
It would fall off when she was
setting up the disguise, wouldn't it?
Then, that empty seat that I saw...
The seat behind Saginuma was free,
so you misunderstood.
What if the seat next to
me hadn't been vacant?
In that case making such a disguise
would have been impossible!
Tsugumi, you had the seat next to him
reserved and didn't cancel it, did you?
By doing so, she would be certain
to ensure a vacant seat next to him.
How could anyone
possibly sleep through...
...having a hat and eye mask
put on them and not wake up?
If the drug to prevent motion sickness
given to Saginuma by Tsugumi was....
...a sleeping pill,
he wouldn't have awakened easily.
A knit hat like Otaka's was
also in Tsugumi's luggage.
If she remembers Otaka’s sleeping
posture, there wouldn't be a problem.
No way...
Tsugumi...
Why?
It’s because of the Grand Prize photo
of the fire incident which he took.
But it was that photo that made both
of you into seeing one another.
That's right.
Because of that photo,
I became interested in him.
The first time I saw his photo,
my heart quivered.
The fear and tragedy of a fire and…
...the preciousness of life.
He was a person who could
express all that in a photo.
In that case, why then!?
Because of that photo, my older
brother's life was taken away!
Could it be that
Otaka himself set that fire...?
Yes.
It had come from his apartment.
The amount of smoke rising up
to my brother's apartment...
...increased by the moment.
I didn't believe it at first.
But, when I asked him about it...
He bragged about it.
A good moment never comes no matter
how long I had been waiting for it.
Unless I made it myself!
Brother! Brother!
I could never forgive him.
That's why...
But this is vexing.
I was confident that
I had hidden the weapon.
When you reached up
for Otaka’s luggage...
For some reason you displayed
some unnatural movement.
When I remembered that,
I was convinced.
The sharpened point of the wire
was touching your skin...
...causing you to hesitate
unconsciously.
Just that?
It wasn't a big thing.
But what should have
been just a casual act...
...looked unnatural in my eyes
and remained in my memory.
It's the small points
which can be overlooked.
That are the most
important points of all.
What's this?
Acting all great...
Thing is, touching a person's
chest to find a clue like that...
That's totally sexual harassment!
Hey! What are you
saying out of the blue!
Eh?!
I... was sleeping?
Ah, oh no!
It’s nothing! It’s nothing.
Sorry.
"Kyoto The Film Studio Mystery Case"
I ended up embarrassed
because of you sleep talking.
"Kyoto"
How persistent! I couldn't help it...
Because we took that flight a year ago
and this one had the same feel to it...
So I unintentionally
had a dream about it.
Is this really the right road?
If we keep going just as we are...
...we'll just arrive at the Sangoji temple,
famous for its sakura trees.
It says that this is a shortcut.
That's strange.
Perhaps it's around here...
Ah! Aren't these...
Lucky Bookmarks that
have been so fashionable lately?
-Lucky Bookmarks?
-I don't know all the details...
But they seem to be pretty
popular on TV and in magazines.
-I don't know all the details though.
-Is that right?
Since we happened to pass by
chance, couldn't we take a little look?
-Right! Right!
-Well, we don't have time...
Welcome!
Our store's lucky bookmarks
brings to both single people...
...and couples and of course you.
With the nice atmosphere
of being a couple...
...and are an extremely popular
matchmaking product.
-Matchmaking?
-Yes.
Is that right? I didn't know
anything about that.
How about this
sakura-colored bookmark?
They're available for
a limited 2 week period...
...and will only be sold
until tomorrow.
Just like with a normal bookmark...
...it's also possible to affix
your names on them.
-Ah...
-What should we do?
Fool.
There's no way I could buy
matchmaking goods.
Ah, here, here!
I've been looking for these!
Hey Mama, since I want to bring
a souvenir for everyone in my class...
...please buy me these.
Well, can't be helped.
Say, weren't you guys
gonna buy some?
Ah, that's okay.
We'll buy some later.
-Right?!
-Eh? Yeah..
Then that's fine!
"Merchandise Sold Out"
It's too bad.
That girl bought up all of them.
We’ll have new stocks
again in the evening.
"Welcome - Kyoto Futomaki Film Studio"
It's more incredible than I thought.
They've even reproduced
the old townscape of Kyoto.
Maybe so!
Why? Are you still angry?
Not really.
I'm not angry!
Is it this way?
Geez! Shinichi!
"Sakuraba, You'll Be Killed"
Who was it that sent me
such a thing!?
It's just a common
harassment letter.
I'm sure it's from a Momoka fan.
It was put in the dressing room.
It's likely that it was the act
of someone working here!
Damn!
They just envy my popularity.
Hey, stop this!
-We're over already!
-I'm worried.
-Isn't this okay?
-Wait...
Ryoma has Oryo, doesn't he?
Don’t worry about Momoka!
I just went out with
that woman for publicity sake.
I guess for me...
It has to be you...
What are you doing?!
You were behaving strangely lately...
But it seems that you're cheating
on me with your ex-girlfriend!
Do you know who you have
to thank for this role?
If you are going to do this,
then I'm going to ruin this film!
Get ready.
-Hey. Chase after her.
-Why?
She might be serious
about ruining this film.
I wouldn't want that.
Even if it's just a small role,
I want to finish it properly.
All right. It'll be okay
if I go after her, right?
Sorry for the interruption.
We didn't mean to eavesdrop or anything.
Where is the shooting spot for the
historical movie, "Ryoma's Holiday"?
-We've gotten lost...
-Ah, that would be here.
Excuse us.
-Ah, you dropped this.
-Ah, thank you.
-Here.
-Ah, thank you very much.
Hey! Wasn't she with the Idol
Hayashibara Momoka and...
...the actor Sakuraba Reiichi
just now?
Sakuraba Reiichi?
Look, it’s the topic everyone’s
been discussing for a while.
Those two have been
seeing each other.
It had been covered on
the "Friday" show.
It’s true that that they’re
passionately in love!
You’re a celebrity nerd...
"Role of Nakaoka Shintaro, Iwasaki Ryuji"
Oh, what's the matter, Momoka?
Could it be you quarreled with
Sakuraba? He's been cocky recently.
Disgusting!
Don't talk to me so casually!
That's dangerous!
I have never seen
a movie set like this before.
It's pretty dusty, isn't it?
Shinichi! Are you okay?!
No, no...
Sorry, sorry, sorry!
I raised the sword and
it just slipped out of my hands.
What are you guys doing here?!
And after all the trouble we went
through to see you, Uncle!
Hey, Dad! If you're not really careful,
there'll be a horrible accident!
Uncle, you need to hold
your sword properly or...
It's Doyle!?
-Ran, you came!
-Kazuha! It's been a while.
Huh, huh? What's this?
You guys know each other?
We solved a case
together once before.
Yeah. I showed Doyle here
my brilliant deductions. Right, Doyle?
-This guy's name is Kudo...
-Do, do...The nickname Doyle…
-I'm turning down this role!
-What are you saying?!
Don't say that Momoka won't
perform the role of Oryo!
Because!
The acting in the Ryoma role
doesn't match up with mine.
That's why either I go or you
change who's playing Ryoma.
Yes!
For the role of Sakamoto Ryoma,
please give it to me, Mori Kogoro.
Uncle!
Read the atmosphere around you!
That's right!
Fumiko could be my replacement?
Ryoma seems to like you as well.
No...
Do you think you're some princess?
I have the leading role!
That leading role was
thanks to me, wasn't it?
Yes, yes. This movie, is thanks
to Momoka's popularity...
...and it also concerns
our sponsors. Right?
Minor roles should keep quiet!
Anyway, I am quitting the role!
You guys...
At this rate, the schedule
will be a mess…
Somehow, this is a disturbing
atmosphere, isn't it?
That Idol's selfishness is
the cause of this.
Isn't this a lover's quarrel
between Sakuraba and her?
It seems that those two are
seeing each other after all?
Talk about Sakuraba and Momoka
has raised their popularity.
It seems that the leading role went to
him because of Momoka's support.
I read in a weekly magazine
that handsome actor...
...has even insured his own face.
Hmpf! That narcissist.
-I heard about that, too.
-Me, too.
Uncle, what are you doing?
An actor's face is their life.
I am pissed!
You idiot, Sakuraba,
angering Momoka like that.
If a popular Idol turns down her
role, my head will fall off first!
I'm sorry!
"Assistant Director: Tanaka Taiki"
"Movie Director: Kashimoto Yoshihiro"
"Popular Idol Hayashibara Momoka and
Hot Actor Inside a Car Making Love!"
Yes. Everyone, thank you for waiting.
We will be shooting scene 44.
Please stand by!
If you would please.
Uncle, do you really want
to go with that look?
-Huh? You have a problem?
-The mustache...Mustache!
The Shinsengumi wouldn't wear
such a mustache!
This is my trademark!
No matter what happens,
I can't shave it off!
-Fight just like we rehearsed.
-Yes!
Then Sakuraba, if you would.
Yes. Is everything okay?
Yes, then Director,
if you would please.
If you would please.
-Then this is the main take!
-Main take!
Okay!
Start!
It's the Shinsengumi!
Hurry and run!
For the sake of official business!
Sakamoto!
Prepare yourself.
Just when you said that the
dawn of Japan is right before us...
Come.
I, Nakaoka Shintaro,
will be your opponent.
Watch out!
Watch out you fools!
Watch out, I said!
Those swords aren't real, right?
That’s impossible, they're fakes.
But those sparks...
There's a device in the sword
that allows electricity...
...to flow out like sparks from them.
As expected of Doyle.
You know a lot, don't you?
You're just like a detective.
I just knew it coincidentally.
That’s all.
-Nakaoka!
-Ryoma!
The rest is up to you...
Okita!
But I can still go on!
I can still go on!
This is bad!
Hattori! Uncle!
Run!
My face!
-My face!
-Reiichi! Reiichi!
Reiichi!
Uncle!
Hattori!
An ambulance! Someone please
call for an ambulance!
Dad, here?
Heiji...
Hattori's unconscious.
Uncle is refusing visitors.
How could this...
What are you doing here?
You and Reiichi are over, aren't you?
Why are you coming to the hospital for?
I was just worried about Sakuraba...
You say such things...
But honestly, you only want to
get back with him, don't you?
Just because your ex-boyfriend
became popular.
-Shameful.
-That's not...
Don't misunderstand.
A supporting actor like you
wouldn't be a match for him.
Sakuraba!
Even with such a minor burn, you
should rest for at least a little longer...
You two stop this.
I could hear you from
the consultation room.
What's with tone of voice?
After I followed you here
to the hospital.
Will your injury be okay?
It's nothing much...
But it is painful as an actor.
What will happen to your role?
After getting the lead role...
I'll have to talk with the Director and
see whether they'll resume with the shoot.
What a fool! What shoot?
Without me, no one
would work with you!
So why don’t you two
get together as unpopular actors...
"Sakuraba, You'll Be Killed"
For now, we are back
at the village set but...
...the shoot might be canceled, right?
With such an explosive accident.
It couldn’t be just an accident.
-Are you Shinichi Kudo?
-Yes. That's right...
I'm Inugai of Kyoto's Prefectural police.
"Kyoto Prefectural Police Detective
- Hajime Inugai"
Oh, sorry, sorry.
Well...
I've heard a lot about you!
One year ago, you splendidly settled
that case on that airliner, didn't you?
That was something.
Ah...
I'd like to hear about
that story sometime...
Sure, but before that,
I would like to study the scene.
-Oh, oh, right! Ah, which way?
-This way.
-Are you a Detective?
-Yes.
I have something to tell you.
Hmm...Sakuraba was sent
a threatening letter, huh...
Does Sakuraba have any ideas
about who it might be?
He was an action actor who
wasn't popular for a long time...
But he met Momoka on a set one day...
And then she introduced
him to various producers...
...and he started picking up
jobs one after another.
Well, thanks to his lover
he became a star.
No surprise that many would
be jealous of him, correct?
Please stop talking that way.
He's been working hard
all this time at it.
Now to have an injury to his face...
Not to be rude, but...
...what sort of relationship
do you have with Sakuraba?
We're just colleagues from
the same theatre group.
That's why I became anxious
about that threatening letter.
Is that right?
Please see to it that Sakuraba
doesn't come into any further danger.
Could it be called
an attempted murder?
There aren’t any traces of gas
leakage or explosive material.
What caused the explosion?
At the time of the explosion...
...fine particles of dust
were dancing around in this area.
Dust?
Dust wouldn't have anything to do
with an explosion, would it?
A dust explosion. (Funjin bakuhatsu)
-Explosive wind? (Fujin bakuhatsu)
-A dust explosion.
It uses the characters for
"powder" and "dirt", so dust.
-Well in essence, fine powder.
-Powder?
Can such an explosion
come from powder?
If you apply fire directly to some
powder, it wouldn't burn much.
But once it comes in contact with
oxygen when it floats in the air...
...it becomes flammable.
And, if one of those particles
comes in contact with fire...
...it spreads quickly around to
all the surrounding powder...
...and explodes with
considerable power.
Throwing up a cloud of dust powder
makes it easily combustible and...
...more particularly
easy to cause an explosion.
The criminal most likely...
Knowing that imitation ash
would be dancing around...
...and that the swords
would be sparking...
...and that the fight would be
performed around the ash cloud...
And replaced the ash
with flour or something...
...so that it would intentionally
explode like that.
When you consider
the threatening letter...
The possibility that a criminal was
targeting Sakuraba would be high...
Well then, have you made an educated
guess as to who the criminal is?
I can't say anything
about that yet...
...but when I consider
candidates for the criminal...
As long as this movie has Momoka,
we'll still be able to salvage it.
Yes.
Yes, I understand.
Don't worry. Yes.
Idiot Producer.
Hey, where's Momoka?
-Tanaka.
-Yes?
Where's Momoka?
Ah, she returned
from the hospital and...
...has locked herself in
the waiting room ever since.
Again?
Whenever she gets in a foul mood,
she shuts herself right away.
-Tanaka.
-Yes?
-Go check on how she's doing.
-Understood.
Momoka.
I need to talk to you.
Momoka?
You in there?
But, the most suspicious person is...
That would be Momoka, right?
Momoka had been quarreling with
Sakuraba before the explosion.
And was talking about
turning down her role.
Well then, that decides it!
The criminal is Momoka!
Momoka!
Please open the door!
Hey! What's going on?
Ah... I am Inugai from
the Kyoto Prefectural police.
Well...The actress isn't coming
out of the waiting room.
-This is the waiting room?
-Yes.
Ohh... That's fine.
Is there really someone in there?
Yes. This room can be locked
only from the inside...
...so someone must be inside.
And this is the only entrance.
It would be a big problem
if she suddenly got sick.
Hey! Hey!
I have no choice but to ram it open.
Okay! All of us ram it!
Yeah, Let's go!
Yes.
3, 2, 1... Go!
Is she dead?
Ran, don't look!
Well... There's no doubt
that this may be suicide.
This happened in a closed
room bolted from the inside.
And if there was a person in there,
he wouldn't be able to get out...
Suicide...
But, why would Momoka...
The cause is the explosion
during your rehearsal.
Explosion...?
The explosion and Momoka's suicide...
How are they connected?
The thing is...
That explosion was not an accident...
It was a case of attempted murder.
Attempted murder?!
What do you mean?
Listen.
That was a wind explosion
planned intentionally.
"Dust" explosion.
Director...
Those prop swords you used
during that fight scene...
They were prepared so they
would give off sparks, right?
Yes. They are often used in
plays to display impact.
What about it?
The criminal knew about the contraption
in those swords which causes sparks...
...and that ash would be flying
around during the fight.
So, he switched the ash in the
fireplace with something flammable…
...like potato starch, and intentionally
caused that explosion.
Hey, that was your
deduction, wasn't it?
Yeah. And he slipped in
a mistake here and there.
And the person who was aiming to
take Sakuraba's life in that explosion...
..was Momoka, who committed suicide.
Sakuraba.You were quarrelling
with Momoka, right?
Impossible. She caused that
explosion over a quarrel...
And you were being threatened too?
How would you know that?
Well... I heard from your fellow actors...
From inside of Momoka's belongings...
...the magazine seemed to be used
for the threatening letter was found.
Here. Look, here.
Anyhow, you were
cheating on her, right?
She's had a grudge
against you this entire time.
That's just slander!
No matter what the motive was...
There’s no denying that
Momoka caused that explosion.
From her belongings...
This was also found.
Although, it still needs to be checked...
But it's most likely the same
powder used in that explosion.
Then I guess...
The explosion was Momoka’s doing, huh...
In other words, Momoka was trying
to kill Sakuraba in the explosion...
but she got scared afterwards
and then committed suicide.
Right, Kudo?
Eh? Ah...
Hmm, but I feel the rope she was hanging
from was too close to the entrance.
Well, that was just by chance, wasn't it?
My thought is that...it wasn't suicide.
What's that?!
It wasn't suicide?Then...
Momoka was murdered.
And the criminal...is most likely in here.
That room was locked from the
inside with a bolt, right?
If she was murdered, how
did the criminal escape?
This isn't some manga or novel...
I'll be solving that trick after this.
No, there isn't any trick!
No matter what you think about
the situation...it was suicide!
It was murder!
-Suicide.
-Murder!
Suicide! Man...
I don't know about you being a high
school detective or something...
...but you're still an amateur.
Hurry back home and sleep...
Hurry! Go home...
Very well. I'll go home and sleep.
Huh?
Eh?! Shinichi?
Shinichi you idiot.
Where have you gone?
Think about how people
are looking for you...
-Thank you very much.
-Not at all...
What was that all about?
What do you mean by that?
What were you and
Fumiko talking about?
What were we talking
about... Bookmarks.
You're buying me one?
Eh?! Ah, well...
Then, I'll take this one!
Since when did you start selling
these sakura bookmarks?
Yes. These sakura-colored
bookmarks are only being sold...
...for a limited time of 2
weeks until tomorrow.
Just like with a normal bookmark,
you can affix your names on them.
Ehh...
These are nice, too... but
why the sakura-colored ones?
Some reason...
I see...
Shinichi! What happened so suddenly?
I know what the trick was!
Eh? Wai, wait... Wait!
Shinichi! Hey! What about
the bookmark!? Hey!
The shoot will continue for now, but...
But with that injury on your face,
you can't have the leading role.
My condolences.
Well... I think you were lucky not
to have died in that explosion.
You sure are talkative, aren't you?
Of course!
It's your fault that Momoka is dead.
Like I thought, that's how it was done...
And?
What sort of trick was it?
The criminal first smuggled a
rope with a hoop in it. And then...
What?! Pausing in the
middle like that is creepy!
Shinichi!
Dad!?
What do you mean by raising your
hand against your own father!?
You were refusing visitors, weren't you?
Your trademark mustache had gotten
burnt, so you wouldn't go out in public!
Wasn't that why you were crying, "No visitors!"?
That’s why! But...
This is a film studio, isn't it?
You were looking for a mustache?!
You must be some extra...
You should be thankful
that you weren’t injured.
Well, your hair was burned though.
Shut up!
They say an actor's face is their life...
And for me, my mustache is
more important than my life!
An actor's face is their life...
Face?
It's Dad's fault this will be so
much trouble to clean up.
Ah. No, no... Don't touch those.
They're scattered around so much.
Ah, not those... Not those either!
That's the one from before.
Eh? From before? Here, here...
Here and here... This might be good too.
Is that how it is...
What is it? What's the matter?
I understand everything now.
The one and only truth!
Heiji...Heiji!
No way, right? Heiji!
The truth is...
I was asked by that high school student
detective to gather all of you together.
Momoka's suicide was a
resolved case, right?
Well, about that...
Momoka didn't commit suicide.
Man, are you still saying that?
This was a closed room.
A murder would be impossible.
I will now expose the
trick behind that.
First, the murderer secretly
brought in a rope with a loop...
Telling her that he wanted to
discuss something with her,
He entered the room and killed Momoka.
And then he tied the rope to the
beam and hung her corpse.
The length of the rope is the highlight of
the trick to turn this into a closed room.
The length of the rope?
It's a pendulum.
Though the criminal was outside of this room,
by using Momoka's body like a pendulum...
...he could lock the room from inside.
First off, the criminal
removed the middle...
...clasp from the tabi
Momoka was wearing.
And then they lightly fixed the
bolt to each side of her feet.
He then raised the
corpse in that condition...
...and out through the open door.
When he released it, the
corpse reacted by swinging inside.
Taking that opportunity to close the doors...
The heels of the corpse would return...
...and strike the door exactly
due to the pendulum action
That was how they
accomplished a closed room.
There are a lot of marks on
both door and the bolt.
Most likely the criminal
experimented many times over...
...in order to accomplish this trick.
In that case, who is the murderer?
The people I could think about...
...were the people who bore a grudge
against Sakuraba and Momoka.
The one with the highest possibility is...
Fumiko... You.
Eh?
Fumiko?
What was her motive?
Jealousy.
Fumiko was jealous of the relationship
between Sakuraba and Momoka.
Why... would I be jealous of those two...
You were Sakuraba's
ex-lover, weren't you?
When I came across you two yesterday, it didn’t look like an ordinary relationship.
To make sure, I confirmed that with
a person from the same theatre group.
But Sakuraba and I had
broke up long ago.
We didn't have any regrets,
so I couldn't be jealous.
Then why were you carrying around
that bookmark like it’s precious?
That's... the matchmaking peddler's
good luck bookmark, isn't it?
The bookmark which you received from
Sakuraba does have both of your names on it.
When I picked it up yesterday,
confirmed it without a doubt.
That was…
I received this from Sakuraba
when we were going out together...
And I just happened to be
carrying it on coincidence.
That would be impossible.
Why?
This sakura-colored bookmark
are limited-time goods...
...and were put up for
sale just 2 weeks ago.
You were carrying around
this bookmark like it’s precious.
This is the evidence that you
still had feelings for Sakuraba.
Fumiko...
Did you really attack me
and murder Momoka?
Sakuraba, do you still
think of me that way?
But...
Fumiko.
If it's difficult for you to talk here,
I'll hear your story at the station...
Ahh!
It's certainly true that I wanted
both of them to die.
Detective.
I hated Sakuraba and that woman.
I and Sakuraba had belonged to the
same theatre group for over 10 years.
And we dreamed of becoming
stars together that entire time.
I felt that it was natural that
I would fall in love with him.
But he even laid hands on that woman.
I was betrayed and only
he had his dream granted.
Having a passionate romance with a
famous Idol as a promotional stunt...
When that explosion occurred and
seeing Sakuraba get his face burned...
I honestly felt relieved.
Then I guess...
The person who killed Momoka...
Beats me.
If the police think so,
then it must be, right?
Fumiko...
Then, Sakuraba.
This time is really farewell.
You have no acting skill,
your face has been injured...
...I think that you will have
hard times from here on...
...but please do the best you can.
Ah, it’s just as I had
deduced in the end.
Kudo. There is always just one truth.
What will happen to Fumiko now?
Because she has voluntarily turned
herself in as a major witness...
Well, a full-fledged
investigation will start now.
"Full-fledged investigation"?
She confessed, didn't she?
No physical evidence has been found yet.
If Fumiko left something behind at the
crime scene that would incriminate her...
...as the criminal, then she will
be identified as the criminal.
Shinichi, it's about time for our bullet train.
Yeah. All right.
You're leaving already?
Though I call myself a detective,
I'm still a high school student.
I have to go to school
I was responsible for the deduction.
The rest is police work.
Well then.
There!
Up there! Here!
Wait, Kazuha! Aren't you overdoing it?
It's my desire to stab the criminal!
There!
Ow, ow, ow!
Dad!
Pops, what are you doing?
In order to get evidence...
...didn’t you tell me to secretly
film using this camera?
Oh no!
Relax.
I struck you with the back of the sword.
Right?
Hattori!
Isn't it about time you gave up?
Playtime is over.
The true criminal is you.
You.
Sakuraba Reiichi.
You...Didn't you leave?
If I was around, I figured
that you would think twice...
...about falsifying evidence,
so I put on that act.
This is where movies are filmed.
Even if we're detectives,
we can put on little acts.
Right, Doyle?
Then...
Making everyone suspect Fumiko...
Of course that was an act.
There was no evidence to prove
that you were the criminal...
...so I had to lead you to this point.
Sakuraba...
You were trying to frame Fumiko by
leaving one of her belongings...
...at the scene of the explosion.
Am I wrong?
I was secretly tailing you with this
camera in order to get evidence.
Yet even so...
Well, with this it's clear that
Sakuraba is the true criminal...
But why did he cause this incident?
For money.
Sakuraba came up with the dust
explosion plot in order to get burns...
...he could then use to collect
a huge insurance payout.
Those rumors about him
insuring his face were true?
When I asked the police to check
with the insurance company...
They said that he was expected to get
an insurance payoff of 300 million yen.
However, his face shouldn’t have
suffered any burns in that explosion.
The evidence for that is...
This was in the costume room.
This is a shooting prop.
Titled "Bankoku Kohou,"
it's a book of international
laws from the Edo period.
It was a book Ryoma was
always carrying with him, right?
Between the pages of this book prop...
There was this.
This is a fireproof material
used in fire doors.
Most likely Sakuraba put this
book inside his costume...
Where it would protect him against
the heat and shock of the explosion.
Even if Sakuraba, in his role as
Ryoma, was found with this book...
He could say that he was role playing
and it wouldn't be unnatural, right?
Right. And, after the explosion...
...he got some charcoal or
something from the fireplace...
...and used it to make a burn as
inconspicuous as possible to his own face.
What's that!?
Hey, you!
Show us your face!
Such an injury could be easily
hidden with make-up, couldn't it?!
Even a small injury is an injury.
By insisting that an actor's
face is their lives...
He was just trying to swindle
his way to an insurance payout.
It’s just as you have said it...
Then, Sakuraba killed Momoka?
Sakuraba's popularity
rose thanks to Momoka.
But she immediately
became disagreeable, didn't she?
That Idol was both
selfish and deeply jealous.
And so you killed her and
made it look like a suicide.
Putting the magazine used to
make the threatening letter...
...and the bag of powder used for
the explosion in Momoka's bag...
You intended to frame
the explosion on her.
The bookmark gift you had given Fumiko...
...was also a tool you used to attract
attention that you had broken up with her.
Anyhow...
By starting a new office
with the insurance money…
You thought that you could make
yourself a star on your own, right? Right!
Trifling with the hearts of two women!
That is absolutely unforgivable!
So what's wrong about it?
What's wrong with using women
who I didn't even like?
I have never loved
either Momoka or Fumiko!
You bastard...
Sakuraba!
Did you ever consider Fumiko's feelings...
...at the time when she
confessed to the crime?
She could come up with...
...many counterarguments
to that level of deduction.
For example, how would it be
possible for a frail woman like her...
...to use her strength and raise a corpse
so it would be seen as a suicide.
In that case...
Why would Fumiko...
Can't you understand that?
Fumiko is still in love with you…
Despite being hurt a lot
by your selfishness.
She was aware of your crime.
But she was never going to admit to that.
Even though you had broken up...
She's been dreaming of you
becoming a star all this time.
How noble!
For the sake of the man she loved,...
...she lied and made herself the criminal...
How would you understand the
feelings of a woman like that?
Fumiko...
For Sakuraba's sake...
...performed a lie as an actress.
But, in her final words…
I think that she was entrusting
her true feelings towards you.
Then, Sakuraba.
This time is really farewell.
Your face has been injured...
...and I think that you will have
hard times from here on…
But please do the best you can.
Fumiko...
I'm sorry.
For bringing you these painful emotions.
Sakuraba...
Fumiko...
You...
Forgive me for acting like that...
Why did you set a trap for me?
I believed in you...
...that this isn’t who you really are.
I...
Damnit…
I am really sorry.
For the sake of exposing the criminal...
I even asked you to perform
the role of a criminal.
I believed in him.
That he couldn't be a murderer.
But then I knew...
After you had solved the trick
of the closed room that...
That was in his attitude.
Fumiko...
Did you really attack me...
...and murder Momoka?"
Even if I couldn’t be there for him...
I at least wanted to watch
over him from a distance.
That’s how I feel even now.
Why would you go that far for him?
Because we are colleagues aiming
to become actors together.
When it comes to a beautiful
woman such as yourself...
You can have many more wonderful
encounters from here on.
This Mori Kogoro guarantees that.
Starting today...
Please start walking
towards a new tomorrow.
And, how about me for starters?
Hey, Dad!
Pops!
Eh? No...
That was a joke. Joke!
Thanks to you, Detective,
I can again start anew.
Thank you.
For finding the one and only truth.
"Filming Canceled"
Well, thanks to Doyle yelling "Escape!"...
...you got away from that
explosion safely, didn't you?
That's true. If it hadn't
been for his voice...
I wouldn't have been able to protect
uncle and jump out the back.
But not going to see off the one who
saved your life is really messed up.
It's fine!
Anyhow, Doyle and I will
have a long relationship.
That Kudo guy...
Still pretending to be
Doyle this time around, too.
Next time I'll be the
one going to Tokyo.
How can your father think that way?
"I guess I'm best suited as being
a detective and not an actor"
Saying that, he hurried back home.
When Fumiko said, "Detective"...
It wasn't about Dad, was it?
I really wonder what sort
of thought circuits he has.
Well, let’s go back home, too.
Yeah!
In the end, he didn't buy me one.
Well then, it couldn't be helped.
This is...?
I was out taking a walk this morning...
...I just happened find it by chance.
Let's hurry and get back.
We'll miss that bullet train.
Shinichi!
Thank you.
OK....
"This Drama is Fictional"